SRUTI MALLIK

srutimallik92@gmail.com · (+1) 314-745-9538 · 720 Eastgate Ave Apt 3N, St Louis, MO 63130

https://smallik92.github.io

https://github.com/smallik92

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/srutimallik-32719a90

SUMMARY

Detail oriented and motivated graduate student with over 4 years of experience in machine learning, statistical modeling, and optimization. Excited to transition into professional roles in the domain of machine/ deep learning and/or computational biology.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

DOCTORAL RESEARCH

- Conceptualized from scratch and coded a generative model of olfactory detection (*Python/MATLAB*) which explained electrophysiological data recorded from locust olfactory circuits. (<u>Code | Publication</u>) SEP 2017 – DEC 2018
- Conceptualized from scratch and coded a generative model of neural and behavioral adaptation (MATLAB) which explained neural imaging and behavioral data from C. elegans.
 JAN 2018 - PRESENT
- Formulating a model (*Python*) that analyzes how algorithms from the reinforcement learning paradigm are implemented in the brain.
 MAY 2020 – PRESENT

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

 Built a Computer Vision model that classified a dataset of 16.5k+ training images comprising of 100+ classes with an accuracy of ~93% using a custom ResNet along with pretrained DenseNet and Xception networks. (Code)
 MAY 2020 – AUG 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LanguagesPython, MATLAB, R, C++, HTML, CSSLibrariesScikit-learn, Numpy, OpenCV, NLTK

Deep Learning Frameworks TensorFlow, Keras

Data Visualization Matplotlib, Seaborn, ggplot2

Database Management SQL, pandas

Cloud Services AWS

EDUCATION

- Washington University in St. Louis, St. Louis, MO, USA
 Ph.D. in Electrical & Systems Engg., 2016-2021, GPA: 3.93/4
 M.S. in Electrical & Systems Engg., 2016-2018, GPA: 3.89/4
- Jadavpur University, Kolkata, WB, India
 B.E. in Electrical Engg., 2011-2015, GPA: 8.95/10

ML EXPERIENCE

Supervised: Generalized linear model, Naïve Bayes, SVM, Decision Trees and

Ensemble Methods

Unsupervised: k-Means, Mixture Models, t-SNE, Anomaly Detection **Computer Vision:** ResNet, Object

Detection (YOLO), U-Net

Sequence Models: RNNs, GRUs,

LSTMs, GloVe

COURSES

Intro. to AI, Intro. to ML, Optimization, Biological Neural Computation, Probability & Stochastic Processes, Deep Learning (Coursera)

AWARDS

Ministry of Human Resource Development, Govt. of India college scholarship (2011-2015)

PUBLICATIONS

- Multiple timescale normative model of neural and behavioral adaptation, Sruti Mallik et al. (in preparation)
- Neural Circuit Dynamics for Sensory Detection, Sruti Mallik et al.; Journal of Neuroscience (2020)

LEADERSHIP

- Mentored one graduate and one undergraduate student in summer research projects (Summer 2020)
- Teaching Assistant for undergraduate course (70+ students, Fall 2019) and graduate course (25+ students, Spring 2018).